<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Englands unanimous senc [sic] to the present Parliament</title>
            <author>J. S., gent.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A61563</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S56</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R27013</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">09614862</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 09614862</idno>
            <idno type="VID">43817</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A61563)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 43817)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1339:27)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Englands unanimous senc [sic] to the present Parliament</title>
                  <author>J. S., gent.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Benjamin Harris,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed: J.S. Gent.</note>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1660-1688 --  Poetry.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:43817:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:43817:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->
            <head>ENGLANDS UNANIMOUS SENC To the preſent PARLIAMENT.</head>
            <l>HEnce ſordid Fear, our ſpirits ſhall not droop,</l>
            <l>We will no more to ſuch diſtraction ſtoop.</l>
            <l>It ſhan't be ſaid we have dejected hearts,</l>
            <l>But that with courage we do act our parts:</l>
            <l>Heroickly our Spirits we'l advance,</l>
            <l>Deſpiſe the Pope and potent King of <hi>France.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Their politick deſigns can't take effect</l>
            <l>Unleſs we ſuffer't by a ſtrange neglect:</l>
            <l>Our ſacred Soveraign for our content</l>
            <l>Hath furniſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d us with a New Parliament;</l>
            <l>Who doubtleſs will make it their greateſt care</l>
            <l>To keep our feet out of a Popiſh ſnare;</l>
            <l>They will with diligence diſſolve our fear,</l>
            <l>No Popiſh Raskal muſt inhabit here.</l>
            <l>Thoſe Fly-blown crew of wicked Popiſh Elves</l>
            <l>May now for paſtime go and hang themſelves:</l>
            <l>Hence then with ſpeed ye Fire-brands of Hell,</l>
            <l>With Loyal Proteſtants ye ſhall not dwell;</l>
            <l>Amongſt the Sheep there is no room for Goats,</l>
            <l>Nor here for Papiſts that would cut our Throats.</l>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:43817:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <l>Therefore abandon us, flie to the Pope,</l>
            <l>Or elſe your necks ſhall ſtretch in Hempen Rope.</l>
            <l>With one accord we gladly now rejoyce,</l>
            <l>And thank the Nation for ſo rare a choice</l>
            <l>Of Knights and Burgeſſes for e'ry Town,</l>
            <l>Which will we hope preſerve our King and Crown.</l>
            <l>And let nothing in competition ſtand</l>
            <l>Againſt the good and ſafeguard of our Land:</l>
            <l>In order thereunto we beg they may</l>
            <l>Obſerve theſe following Maxims e'ry day:</l>
            <l>After that happy day wherein you meet</l>
            <l>And are well ſeated in your Judgment-ſeat,</l>
            <l>Send for thoſe Traitors now within the Tower,</l>
            <l>And let them have their merits by your Power:</l>
            <l>Forthwith to Juſtice do ſuch Traitors bring,</l>
            <l>That dare preſume againſt our gracious King</l>
            <l>To act ſuch Villanies with baſe conſent,</l>
            <l>As to ſubvert our happy Government.</l>
            <l>When that is done, let all thoſe Popiſh Knaves</l>
            <l>That have endeavour'd for to make us Slaves,</l>
            <l>Receive this ſentence with a joint conſent,</l>
            <l>From <hi>England</hi> a perpetual Baniſhment.</l>
            <l>Next unto this, ſee how our Fleet doth ſtand,</l>
            <l>Let not a Rebel have in it Command;</l>
            <l>Let no ſuſpected perſon have a Power,</l>
            <l>We ſhall be then in danger e'ry hour.</l>
            <l>When this is done, and all our Fleet ſecure,</l>
            <l>The Force of <hi>French</hi> or <hi>Turk</hi> we can endure.</l>
            <l>And for our ſafety, pray ſecure our Ports,</l>
            <l>See who are made Commanders in our Forts;</l>
            <l>Let none be there but ſuch as are well known</l>
            <l>To be true Subjects to our King alone;</l>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:43817:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->
            <l>Such as have courage and are known to be</l>
            <l>True Proteſtants, of faithful Loyalty;</l>
            <l>And will with diligence diſcharge their truſt,</l>
            <l>And prove to King and Country True and Juſt:</l>
            <l>Then may we ſay, we fear no Foraign parts,</l>
            <l>Nor Popiſh Blood-hounds with their Magick arts.</l>
            <l>After our Sea Ports thus in ſafety ſtands,</l>
            <l>And are intruſted under good Commands,</l>
            <l>Then to ſecure us from all further harms,</l>
            <l>See who are made Commanders now at Arms;</l>
            <l>Let Horſleach Papiſts all be quite debarr'd</l>
            <l>Of any Office in our Martial Guard;</l>
            <l>For if they once ſhould come into the Field,</l>
            <l>To their commanding power we muſt yield:</l>
            <l>Like greedy Wolves they'd ſeize us as their Prey,</l>
            <l>And murder Proteſtants both night and day:</l>
            <l>Thus ſhall we be tormented at their Will,</l>
            <l>Until of Loyal blood they've ſuck'd their fill.</l>
            <l>Then will the Loyal Proteſtants decay,</l>
            <l>When once the Popiſh Blood-hounds bear the ſway.</l>
            <l>To ſave us then from dangers eminent,</l>
            <l>You are our Guides, moſt Noble Parliament:</l>
            <l>Our Body Politick is much diſeas'd,</l>
            <l>And only by your Power can be eas'd;</l>
            <l>It's only you that can our pain deſcry,</l>
            <l>And eaſe the Torture of our Malady:</l>
            <l>When by your skill the trembling Pulſe you feel</l>
            <l>Of this our weak and tottering Common-weal,</l>
            <l>You ſoon will find our body Politick</l>
            <l>Of an Infectious Pain lies very ſick;</l>
            <l>And therefore muſt be Purg'd with care and ſpeed,</l>
            <l>And you are they that muſt perform this Deed.</l>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:43817:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
            <l>Purge er'e vein let not our Loyal blood</l>
            <l>Be putrifi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d with Papiſts, Hells choice brood:</l>
            <l>Then may we all unanimouſly ſay,</l>
            <l>A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> our Foes, bleſt be that happy day</l>
            <l>Wherein our Parliament did firſt appear,</l>
            <l>To be ſo kind thus to diſſolve our fear;</l>
            <l>Then may we ſay we are in hopes to ſee</l>
            <l>Not only Months but Years of Jubilee,</l>
            <l>The juſt complaints of a decaying Trade</l>
            <l>Which formerly with ſorrow we have made</l>
            <l>Muſt then be buried, none can then complain,</l>
            <l>For Trade will flouriſh in our Land again.</l>
            <l>For which I wee'l render, as we ought to do,</l>
            <l>Thanks to our Royal Soveraign and you;</l>
            <l>Whom God preſerve from dangers, and defend</l>
            <l>The Faith of Proteſtants; and ſo we end.</l>
            <byline>By <hi>J. S.</hi> Gent.</byline>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Benjamin Harris</hi> at the <hi>Stationers-Arms</hi> in the <hi>Piazza</hi> under the <hi>Royall Exchange</hi> in <hi>Cornhill.</hi> 1680.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:43817:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
